When our world ended, their mission began.
9 is a action, adventure, animation film directed by Shane Acker.
When 9 first comes to life, he finds himself in a post-apocalyptic world.
All humans are gone, and it is only by chance that he discovers a small community of others like him
taking refuge from fearsome machines that roam the earth intent on their extinction.
Despite being the neophyte of the group, 9 convinces the
others that hiding will do them no good.
#9 (voice), played by Elijah Wood.
#1 (voice), played by Christopher Plummer.
#2 (voice), played by Martin Landau.
#5 (voice), played by John C. Reilly.
#6 (voice), played by Crispin Glover.
#7 (voice), played by Jennifer Connelly.
9 is a 2009 animated post-apocalyptic science fiction horror thriller film directed by Shane
Acker based on his 2005 short film created at the UCLA Animation Workshop.
The film was written by Pamela Pettler and produced by Jim Lemley,
Tim Burton, Timur Bekmambetov and Dana Ginsburg.
Set in an alternate version of the 1940s, the film follows a rag doll labeled "9" who
awakens shortly after the end of humanity following the uprising of machines.
The film features the voices of Elijah Wood, John C.
Reilly, Jennifer Connelly, Christopher Plummer and Crispin
Glover, with Martin Landau and Fred Tatasciore.
9 was released by Focus Features in theatres on September 9, 2009.
The film received generally mixed reviews from critics, earned $48.4 million on a $30 million budget and received an
Outstanding Producer of Animated Theatrical Motion Pictures nomination in 21st Producers Guild of America Awards.
The film was released on DVD and Blu-ray on December 29, 2009.
Since its release, the film has been critically re-assessed more positively for its animation, themes,
world design, horror elements and dark atmosphere, and has gained a cult following.
The film explores themes of friendship, man vs machine,
hope, dystopia, post-apocalyptic future.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.